Visa Status: Need Visa

Personal Statement: Quest to work in a professional and challenging atmosphere to utilize the skills with the emerging latest technologies with the scope for widening the spectrum of my knowledge for better growth of organization

Experience: Overall 7+ years' experience in Development & Architecture Roles with Team Handling and Continuous Support. Worked on Agile and Waterfall Methodologies also Version Control Tools like TFS and GIT.

CONTACT

Address

A-519, Avantika, Sector-2, Rohini, Delhi

Phone

+91-8800641354

Email

deepakkanswal@gmail.com

DETAILS

Nationality

Indian

Date of Birth

01 August 1988

Marital Status

Unmarried

DEEPAK SHARMA

Sr. Software Engineer/Full Stack Developer

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Anthology Inc (CMMI-5)

October 2018 - Present

- **Technologies Used:** C #, SQL Server-2014, Stored Procedures, AJAX, HTML, CSS, LINQ, EF, Angular, MVC & Bootstrap.
- **Projects:** DVet, Maha IT, PMKVY, TNSDC and Hostel Management.
- Choose Architecture and model for projects. Choose right technology tools and dividing tasks among teams using various modules. Understanding Client Requirements and act accordingly.
- Continually improved knowledge, skills and performance based on feedback and self-identified professional developmental needs. Enhance the online experience of our customers by designing and delivering efficient systems.

System Analyst, Eon Technologies, (Banking Domain) Gurugram, India

August 2017 - September 2018

- **Technologies Used:** C #, SQL Server-2012, Stored Procedures, AJAX, HTML, CSS, LINQ, EF, AngularJS, MVC & Bootstrap.
- Projects: Mobias Banca, ABHA, BCR.
- Participation in all aspects of the development process including architecture-design, development, testing, code reviews, deployments, etc.
- Investigates and implements new technologies where appropriate. Efficiently and Timely execute Sprint Plans.
- Good people skills, be able to connect with each team member. Works as a mentor for Junior Developers
- The process includes all the activities of online banking i.e
 Funds Transfer, Add Beneficiary, Transfer between own/other
 accounts, Foreign Currency Exchange including others.
 Deals with the online banking for Corporate and Personal
 Banking. Have to develop the project, module wise with help
 of client interactions.

LINKS

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/deep ak-sharma-8baa86190/

KEY SKILLS

- ✓ C#
- ✓ Microsoft SQL Server
- ✓ Team Foundation Server (TFS) / GIT
- √ jQuery
- ✓ SQL
- ✓ ASP.NFT
- ✓ JavaScript
- ✓ Angular
- ✓ ASP.NET MVC
- ✓ Bootstrap
- ✓ Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
- ✓ ASP.NET Core
- ✓ Entity Framework (EF) Core
- ✓ Entity Framework
- ✓ Web Services API
- ✓ AGILE
- ✓ Full-Stack Development

LANGUAGES

Hindi English

HOBBIES

Tech News Reading Writing Sports Learning New Skills

Interface Software Services,

February 2012 - December 2015

- Started Work in Dotnet technologies with Sql and Front End languages like HTML and Jquery.
- Interacting with clients and understand their needs.
- Web Hosting and movement to server.
- Build End to End project for various domains.

EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science And Engineering, Haryana, India

July 2008 - June 2011

- Graduated: 67%
- Internship: IICE Technologies for Dotnet Project
- Workshop: Made a website for Electric Goods Company
- Professional development courses: C#, SQL, Dotnet, HTML
- Awarded: Distinction

Senior Secondary School (CBSE Board), Remal Public School, Delhi, India

March 2005 - February 2006

- Major Subjects: Computers, Mathematics, English, Physics & Chemistry
- Graduated: 73%

High School (CBSE Board), Mother Divine Public School, Delhi, India

March 2003 - February 2004

- Major Subjects: Science, Mathematics, Social Science, Hindi and English
- Graduated: 70%

Projects Worked

Project Name : BankFlex (August-2017 to September-2018)

Skills Used : C #, SQL Server-2014, Stored Procedures, AJAX, HTML, CSS, LINQ, EF, Angular, MVC.

About Project: The process includes all the activities of online banking i.e Funds Transfer, Add Beneficiary, Transfer between own/other accounts, Foreign Currency Exchange including others. Deals with the online banking for Corporate and Personal Banking. Have to develop the project, module wise with client interactions.

Project Name : MahalT (October-2018 to March-2019)

Skills Used : C #, SQL Server-2016, Stored Procedures, AJAX, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, MVC, LINQ, Angular.

About Project: This Project is CRM for the Maharastra University. It covers all aspects beginning from the registration of a new student in the college along with maintaining attendance and marks of every student. In this project, the retrieval of information is done through an INTRANET bases campus wide portal. Information is collected from all the departments and files are created for measuring individual and overall performance.

Project Name: Padhan Mantri Kaushal Vikas Yojna (March-2019 till date)

Skills Used : C #, SQL Server-2014, AJAX, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, Angular, Bootstrap, LINQ, JSON, MVC.

About Project: This is a PAN India Project. Pradhan Mantri Kaushal Vikas Yojana (PMKVY) is the flagship scheme of the Ministry of Skill Development & Entrepreneurship (MSDE). The objective of this Skill Certification Scheme is to enable a large number of Indian youth to take up industry-relevant skill training that will help them in securing a better livelihood. Individuals with prior learning experience or skills will also be assessed and certified under Recognition of Prior Learning (RPL). Under this Scheme, Training and Assessment fees are completely paid by the Government.

The above-mentioned projects are some of my works among many others.